If you're looking for trouble...he's Joe Kidd.
Joe Kidd is a western, drama film directed by John Sturges.
A band of Mexicans find their U.
land claims denied and all the records destroyed in a courthouse fire.
Their leader, Louis Chama, encourages them to use force to regain their land.
A wealthy landowner wanting the same decides to hire a gang
of killers with Joe Kidd to track Chama.
Joe Kidd, played by Clint Eastwood.
Frank Harlan, played by Robert Duvall.
Luis Chama, played by John Saxon.
Lamarr Simms, played by Don Stroud.
Helen Sanchez, played by Stella Garcia.
Mingo, played by James Wainwright.
Joe Kidd is a 1972 American Revisionist Western film starring Clint Eastwood and
Robert Duvall, written by Elmore Leonard and directed by John Sturges.
The film is about an ex-bounty hunter hired by a wealthy landowner named Frank Harlan to track
down Mexican revolutionary leader Luis Chama, who is fighting for land reform.
It forms part of the Revisionist Western genre.
The film explores themes of cowboy, gun violence, steam
locomotive, gunfighter, gun for hire.
The tone is emotional.